<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Day 1 - Networking fundamentals on Amazon CloudOps Networking Workshop</title>
    <link>/day-1-networking-foundations.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Day 1 - Networking fundamentals on Amazon CloudOps Networking Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/day-1-networking-foundations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is a network?</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/network-definition.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/network-definition.html</guid>
      <description>A network can be defined as a group of devices interconnected together via an edge networking component forming a dedicated and private environment.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example:
There are several types of networks but the most common are LAN (Local Area Network) and WAN (Wide Area Network). As the names indicate, a LAN is defined by a single network (i.e. your house network) while a WAN allows interconnection between different LANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSI Model</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/osi-model.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/osi-model.html</guid>
      <description>Networking is based on the OSI model:
Each layer has a meaning in networking. We will not cover the layers in dept, but you can read more about in the Further Reading section.
Networking is based on the OSI model, it is a bit like the layers of a cake, often referred as L1, L2, L3, etc..
Let&amp;rsquo;s pick some real life examples:
  L1 = your home router, your cables</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subnetting</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/subnetting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/subnetting.html</guid>
      <description>A network (or LAN) is defined by a a block of IP addresses called a CIDR block, from which every host in the network receives an IP address.
A CIDR indicates the size of a network, and networks are calculated with subnetting. Subnetting allows the segmentation of a bigger network in smaller networks. For example, a company could have different departments (HR, Finances, etc) and therefore wish to seggregate their corporate network based on these departments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/routing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/routing.html</guid>
      <description>The way machines talk to each others is via routing tables, and that is the router&amp;rsquo;s responsibility.
A routing table is like a map for routers to send traffic to and from.
Picture with A to B with route table.
Then show OSPF/BGP -&amp;gt; LAN/WAN.
Show ping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS/DHCP</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/dnsdhcp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/dnsdhcp.html</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s DNS? Record types. Real life example. Application example.
What;s DHCP? How does it work with DNS? Give example of home network, or VoIP phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/homework.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/homework.html</guid>
      <description>Link and instructions for a lab. Subnetting exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
