<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking Fundamentals on Amazon CloudOps Networking Workshop</title>
    <link>/day-1-networking-foundations.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking Fundamentals on Amazon CloudOps Networking Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/day-1-networking-foundations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is a network?</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/network-definition.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/network-definition.html</guid>
      <description>A network can be defined as a group of devices interconnected together via an edge networking component forming a dedicated and private environment.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example:
There are several types of networks but the most common are LAN (Local Area Network) and WAN (Wide Area Network). As the names indicate, a LAN is defined by a single network (i.e. your house network) while a WAN allows interconnection between different LANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OSI Model</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/osi-model.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/osi-model.html</guid>
      <description>Networking is based on the OSI model:
Each layer has a meaning in networking. We will not cover the layers in depth, but you can read more about in the Further Reading section.
Networking is based on the OSI model, it is a bit like the layers of a cake, often referred as L1, L2, L3, etc..
Let&amp;rsquo;s pick some real life examples:
  L1 = a router, a switch, a cable, anything physical</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subnetting</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/subnetting.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/subnetting.html</guid>
      <description>A network (or LAN) is defined by a a block of IP addresses called a CIDR block, from which every host in the network receives an IP address.
A CIDR indicates the size of a network, and networks are calculated with subnetting. Subnetting allows the segmentation of a bigger network in smaller networks. For example, a company could have different departments (HR, Finances, etc) and therefore wish to segregate their corporate network based on these departments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routing</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/routing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/routing.html</guid>
      <description>The router comes into the picture when different hosts from different networks try to communicate. We have seen in a previous section that the router does all the routing to allow the internal hosts to talk to an external destination such as the Internet or just another network.
This communication is done by the means of routing tables and routing protocols.
A route table is a source/destination map for the router to know where to send the traffic, based on the traffic destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS/DHCP</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/dnsdhcp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/dnsdhcp.html</guid>
      <description>Domain Name System (DNS): DNS stands for Domain Name System and it is used in our everyday tasks without even realising it. DNS can be compared to an address book since it is a directory of mappings between names and IP addresses and allows hosts to reach endpoints such as URLs or other machines.
The full name of a server or endpoint is made of a hostname and the domain in which it sits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework</title>
      <link>/day-1-networking-foundations/homework.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/day-1-networking-foundations/homework.html</guid>
      <description>Subnetting Exercice  192.168.0.5/16  What is the binary address of 192.168.0.5?
What is the network ID?
What is the subnet mask?
What is the gateway router IP address?
How many IP addresses in this network?
 172.31.10.10/25  What is the binary address of 172.31.10.10?
What is the network ID?
What is the subnet mask?
What is the gateway router IP address?
How many IP addresses in this network?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
